# MICHAEL BALLARD

Software developer





An ambitious developer with 3 years of experience in a wide range of languages and technologies, with a goal to learn and master front end or full stack development. I am especially keen to persue React and React Native development.

#### WORK EXPERIENCES

#### **Graduate Techboost Project**

Vodafone | December 2019 - Present

- Currently developing a React Native mobile app for new starters at Vodafone.
- Ran workshops for my team to introduce them to mobile app development and React Native.
- Led development for the app and helped members of the team with issues they encountered.
- Took part in UX and UI workshops with senior developers in Vodafone to learn best practice and get feedback from professionals.

### Solutions Engineer - IoT

**Vodafone** | September 2019 - Present

- Developed IoT solutions for customers using JavaScript on our Invent platform.
- Integrated with 3rd party APIs to expand our IoT capability.
- Involvement in client workshops to understand requirements and interate projects in an agile manner.
- Ran workshops with the team to introduce them to various technologies such as React Native, Microsoft Flow and Python programming.

## Automation Developer - Big Data Platforms & Services

Vodafone | April - September 2019

- Prototyped various machine learning solutions as a POC for reducing manual effort across the Big Data space.
- Developed an intent-analyis algorithm in Python which was used on support tickets to predict with 95% accuracy what department a ticket should be allocated to.
- Aided in development of a Machine Learning model to predict the closure category of tickets.
- Demoed prototypes to senior managers to demostrate the value of automated solutions.

#### PPMO Coordinator - Vodafone Business

**Vodafone** | September 2018 - March 2019

- Aided project managers with issues that arose with clients or project teams.
- Developed a reporting dashboard using SAP Business Objects to allow senior managers to get an overview of their project teams and areas of concern.
- Created a website to showcase a new file sharing capability within the department.
- Automated some data entry tasks using Python to allow realocation of resources.

# Junior Developer

**Gloversure** I August 2016 - May 2017

- My first professional experience of web and mobile app design.
- Developed a mobile app using the lonic framework for customers to be able to manage their site content from their phone.
- Developed a PHP application to enable the marketting team to create mobile notifications for customers.
- Modernised a lot of legacy code. Most noteably AJAXified the CMS to enable dynamic content and less page redirects.

#### PROJECTS - CAN BE SEEN ON MY GITHUB, LINKED ABOVE.

#### React Native animated login UI

Learnt the basics of React Native reanimated animation by creating a sleek login UI with performant animations.

# Covid19 Tracker

Developed a web app using React to visualise the spread of coronavirus using the covid19 API.

#### Sports Team Website

Used React to create a website for a sports team, using various google APIs to pull in scores from a spreadsheet and images/files from a google drive folder.

#### SKILLS

#### **Technical**

JavaScript ES6/TypeScript

ReactJS/React Native

Firebase/AWS Cloud services

Python

PHP

SQL

#### **Professional**

Effective communicator

Confident leader

Willingness to help others

Good time management

#### Other skills

Photography and Filming

Photoshop and Video editing

Good knowledge of PC Hardware

Inevitably acting as tech support for my whole family

#### EDUCATION

#### **BSc in Computer Science**

Aberystwyth University 2014 - 2018

#### Warwick School

GCSE and A Level 2007 - 2014

#### LANGUAGES

English (Native)

### INTERESTS

Photography

Mountain biking

Gaming

Anything Elon Musk is doing